<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The world according to Joakim</title>
    <link>http://www.joakimsk.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The world according to Joakim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:04:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.joakimsk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>birth of a blog</title>
      <link>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/birth-of-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:04:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/birth-of-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years, I have wrestled with lack of focus and attention. Would I give myself a diagnosis, I would say I have ADHD. But I hate labels, and I believe we are all a little bit crazy, some more than others, but nobody is normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed an outlet, a place to put down what is inside of my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several failed attempts at maintaining a Wordpress-site, or pure HTML sites, I gave up. My head was, and for the foreseeable future, would remain a total mess, clogged with thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one last, final attempt at making a single archive of the world as I see it. If I fail keeping this up, I recon I will never manage to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set up using hugo, a static site generator, and hosted by github, to ensure it will remain up even if/when I run out of money. Even when I die. Pretty nifty, huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to get your thoughts on the matters at hand, and I ask you to send me an email if you have any input. If it is interesting and useful, I may add it to the posts where applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the content here will be highly &lt;strong&gt;subjective&lt;/strong&gt;.
Yes, some of it may also be &lt;strong&gt;controversial&lt;/strong&gt;.
Yes, things may get &lt;strong&gt;crazy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;em&gt;The world according to Joakim&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>