<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The world according to Joakim</title>
    <link>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The world according to Joakim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 23:04:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.joakimsk.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>solitude is bliss</title>
      <link>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/solitude-is-bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 23:04:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/solitude-is-bliss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isolation is a way to know ourselves. &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years, I have been searching for methods to calm the storm in my mind. The constant flow of thoughts, emotions and ideas that come in the most distracting fashion throughout the day- and night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some years ago, I watched Samsara for the first time in my life, remembering scenes of contrast, humanity on its best and worst. A scene struck out to me as immensely beautiful. A wide view of the plains in Bagan, Myanmar, green as far as the eye could see, with religious buildings, pagodas in vast numbers. Pagodas built by hand over the period of over a thousand years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see these creations of mankind, made by hand for no other appearant reason than to house a relic shrine, often a golden buddha at its centre, standing there as the sun moves over the sky, replaced by a star-filled night, before it all repeats itself again the coming morning. That seed sprouted, and over time, got watered as I aged slowly in this life which is so finite and short in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By September 2016, the sprout had rooted properly. I was feeling how my work was changing me and my views in a direction which I disagreed with, and I felt at bad terms with myself. Every morning I woke up with a hope to turn around, but by the end of the day, I went to bed again with feelings and emotions just compounding. Exploitation was on my mind, taking part in the big wheels of capitalism, using and pressing margins for my own survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One evening, I remembered a meditation course that some friends have gone through with benefit. As it happens, I did swiftly read about it even earlier, around the age of 17 when much time was spent online, hiding from the reality around me. Considering how far away the meditation centers seemed, I dismissed that idea at that time. Now, however, I was at the age of 27. Seeing that it was worth a shot, also for the sake of maybe getting into good routines with meditation to relax the mind, I signed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One does often say that it is the first step that is the hardest, and it surely was for me when I was considering to sign up for this meditation course. A sudden feelig of relief came sweeping over me as I submitted my application. A few weeks after, I got accepted, and started booking flight tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course was teaching a technique of Vipassana Meditation, originally discovered by Gautama Buddha, it is said. Not religious by nature, it allows for anyone to practice without spiritual or religious conflict. My meditation centre would be located near Mandlalay, Myanmar, just a short bus-ride from Bagan, Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These centres are found all around the world, but I felt a pull towards Myanmar, which also coincidently turned out to be the country which have kept Vipassana Meditation pure throughout time, and thus can be seen as one of the more traditional places to take this course. This I did not know before I arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Franz Kafka
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>archlinux on odroid-c1</title>
      <link>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/arch-odroid-c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 19:30:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/arch-odroid-c1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;note-to-future-self&#34;&gt;Note to future self&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in order to install Archlinux on the Odroid-C1, make sure you have an existing Ubuntu-machine running. If you do not have, download the Ubuntu image on your Mac or Windows, then write an SD-card that you can use on the Odroid in order to have an Ubuntu-environment to set up the Archlinux onto the EMMC or another SD-card. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-your-mac-os-x&#34;&gt;On your Mac OS X&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget http://de.eu.odroid.in/ubuntu_14.04lts/ubuntu-14.04.3lts-lubuntu-odroid-c1-20151020.img.xz
# Remember to verify the md5!
unxz ubuntu-14.04.3lts-lubuntu-odroid-c1-20151020.img.xz

# Check the ID for your SD card, replace # with ID number
df -h

sudo diskutil unmountDisk /dev/disk#
sudo dd bs=1m if=ubuntu-14.04.3lts-lubuntu-odroid-c1-20151020.img of=/dev/rdisk#
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, place your SD card containing Lubuntu into your Odroid-C1, and boot it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-your-odroid-c1-running-lubuntu&#34;&gt;On your Odroid-C1 running Lubuntu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Default user/pass is odroid/odroid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the official guide on getting Archlinux.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://archlinuxarm.org/platforms/armv7/amlogic/odroid-c1&#34;&gt;https://archlinuxarm.org/platforms/armv7/amlogic/odroid-c1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, boot up the Archlinux EMMC on your Odroid-C1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-your-odroid-c1-running-archlinux&#34;&gt;On your Odroid-C1 running Archlinux&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the HDMI output should be enabled, and drop you to a command-line interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Default user/pass is alarm/alarm, and root-password is root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some packages I installed, for my usecase:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;su #elevate privileges to root user
pacman -Syu
pacman -S iperf3
pacman -S git
pacman -S sudo # remember to visudo and add %wheel
pacman -S gcc
pacman -S wget
pacman -S python3
pacman -S gawk
pacman -S vim
pacman -S python-numpy
pacman -S python-requests
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice how the hardware command line cursor is nowhere to be seen. This can be hacked back in place.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://archlinuxarm.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=63&amp;amp;t=8389&amp;amp;sid=a6ad39e390afa9e9d1a5533fe9e080eb&amp;amp;start=10&#34;&gt;https://archlinuxarm.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=63&amp;amp;t=8389&amp;amp;sid=a6ad39e390afa9e9d1a5533fe9e080eb&amp;amp;start=10&lt;/a&gt;
From your home directory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#infocmp &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/terminfo.txt
#sed -i.bak -e &#39;s/?0c/?112c/g&#39; -e &#39;s/?8c/?48;0;64c/g&#39; terminfo.txt
#tic terminfo.txt
#tput cnorm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Must run tput cnorm later on after a reboot, I think, so put it somewhere smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the LCD 16x2 using the HD44780 controller. Examples show using the wiringPi made by Gordon at &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiringpi.com/&#34;&gt;http://wiringpi.com/&lt;/a&gt; however the version maintained by Gordon is unable to detect the Odroid hardware. Thus, they have a fork of an old version hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hardkernel/wiringPi&#34;&gt;https://github.com/hardkernel/wiringPi&lt;/a&gt; which Hardkernel has modified to fit the Odroid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid running gpio using root, create a new group that can access gpio.
We have to identify the device used in sysfs, which is in this case (236, 0) named meson-gpiomem.
udev is used to make rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;as-root&#34;&gt;As root:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;groupadd -f -r gpio
usermod -G gpio alarm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cd /etc/udev/rules.d/
touch 99-gpio.rules&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add content to 99-gpio.rules based on information from running:
udevadm info /dev/gpiomem # Outputs information about the virtual device
devadm info &amp;ndash;attribute-walk &amp;ndash;path=/sys/class/gpio/ # Outputs information about the class gpio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More useful info can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://derekmolloy.ie/writing-a-linux-kernel-module-part-2-a-character-device/&#34;&gt;http://derekmolloy.ie/writing-a-linux-kernel-module-part-2-a-character-device/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SUBSYSTEM==&amp;quot;meson-gpiomem&amp;quot;, KERNEL==&amp;quot;gpiomem&amp;quot;, GROUP=&amp;quot;gpio&amp;quot;, MODE=&amp;quot;0660&amp;quot;
SUBSYSTEM==&amp;quot;gpio&amp;quot;, KERNEL==&amp;quot;gpiochip*&amp;quot;, ACTION==&amp;quot;add&amp;quot;, PROGRAM=&amp;quot;/bin/sh -c &#39;chown root:gpio /sys/class/gpio/export /sys/class/gpio/unexport ; chmod 220 /sys/class/gpio/export /sys/class/gpio/unexport&#39;&amp;quot;
SUBSYSTEM==&amp;quot;gpio&amp;quot;, KERNEL==&amp;quot;gpio*&amp;quot;, ACTION==&amp;quot;add&amp;quot;, PROGRAM=&amp;quot;/bin/sh -c &#39;chown root:gpio /sys%p/active_low /sys%p/direction /sys%p/edge /sys%p/value ; chmod 660 /sys%p/active_low /sys%p/direction /sys%p/edge /sys%p/value&#39;&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reboot odroid to reload rules&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to use the sysfs interface and fiddle for testing purposes. It is adviced to avoid using this for applications if there are existing kernel drivers available.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/gpio/sysfs.txt&#34;&gt;https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/gpio/sysfs.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about kernel modules, see here &lt;a href=&#34;http://derekmolloy.ie/writing-a-linux-kernel-module-part-1-introduction/&#34;&gt;http://derekmolloy.ie/writing-a-linux-kernel-module-part-1-introduction/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPIO=101 # Select GPIO #101 (GPIOX.BIT4 or wiringPi#21), this is on pin #29 on Odroid-C1
echo $GPIO &amp;gt; /sys/class/gpio/export
echo &amp;quot;out&amp;quot; &amp;gt; /sys/class/gpio/gpio$GPIO/direction
echo 1 &amp;gt; /sys/class/gpio/gpio$GPIO/value
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To watch gpio events, a nice guy made a nice small program in C. When an interrupt is observed, the program executes a script. Can be detached. Nifty. But it does rely on sysfs. Oh well.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/larsks/gpio-watch&#34;&gt;https://github.com/larsks/gpio-watch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/larsks/gpio-watch.git
cd gpio-watch
make
mkdir gpio-scripts
touch gpio-scripts/102
# Set up script in 102 and chmod +x
./gpio-watch -s gpio-scripts -e switch 102 # 102 is left LCD 16x2 button
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an alternative, one could maybe make a kernel module, following this series
&lt;a href=&#34;http://derekmolloy.ie/kernel-gpio-programming-buttons-and-leds/&#34;&gt;http://derekmolloy.ie/kernel-gpio-programming-buttons-and-leds/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the future, consider trying to build image using Yocto.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Nuand/bladeRF/wiki/Creating-Linux-based-Embedded-System-Images-with-Yocto&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Nuand/bladeRF/wiki/Creating-Linux-based-Embedded-System-Images-with-Yocto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>birth of a blog</title>
      <link>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/birth-of-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 20:04:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joakimsk.com/post/birth-of-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years, I have wrestled with lack of focus and attention. Would I give myself a diagnosis, I would say I have ADHD. But I hate labels, and I believe we are all a little bit crazy, some more than others, but nobody is normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed an outlet, a place to put down what is inside of my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several failed attempts at maintaining a Wordpress-site, or pure HTML sites, I gave up. My head was, and for the foreseeable future, would remain a total mess, clogged with thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one last, final attempt at making a single archive of the world as I see it. If I fail keeping this up, I recon I will never manage to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set up using hugo&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator, and hosted by github&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, to ensure it will remain up even if/when I run out of money. Even when I die. Pretty nifty, huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to get your thoughts on the matters at hand, and I ask you to send me an email if you have any input. If it is interesting and useful, I may add it to the posts where applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the content here will be highly &lt;strong&gt;subjective&lt;/strong&gt;.
Yes, some of it may also be &lt;strong&gt;controversial&lt;/strong&gt;.
Yes, things may get &lt;strong&gt;crazy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;em&gt;The world according to Joakim&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>